<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter
	id="pre-requisites">
	<title>Pre-Requisites</title>
 <para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;'s core requirement is Java. The following table details the Hardware, Operating System and Software requirements for a clean installation of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;. 
<table
						frame="all"
						pgwide="1">
						<title>Installation Pre-Requisites</title>
						<tgroup cols='3' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
							<colspec
								colnum="1"
								colname="c0" />
							<colspec
								colnum="2"
								colname="c1" />
							<colspec
								colnum="3"
								colname="c2" />
							<thead>
								<row>
									<entry>Component</entry>
									<entry>Requirement</entry>
									<entry>Notes</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry>System Requirements</entry>
									<entry>Intel Pentium 1 GHz or faster for simple applications. Hard disk space of at least 10GB. RAM of at least 1.5 GB</entry>	
									<entry>Higher the RAM and processing power, better is the throughput</entry>	
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>TDM Hardware (Optional)</entry>
									<entry>
										&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; supports legacy E1/T1 links via SS7 cards. You must have <literal>dahdi</literal> or <literal>dialogic</literal> cards installed along with their native libraries.
										&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; also supports SIGTRAN (M3UA). 
									</entry>	
									<entry>In case if you are connecting to core network via SIGTRAN, TDM hardware is not needed.</entry>	
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Operating System</entry>
									<entry>
										The platform can be installed on any OS that supports Java.
										But native libraries for SS7 cards are compiled only for Linux at the moment and therefore supported only on Linux Operating System.
									</entry>
									<entry>The libraries for SS7 cards will be compiled for Windows in future releases. For SIGTRAN the OS should support SCTP protocol.</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Java</entry>
									<entry>You must have a working Java Runtime Environment (JRE) or Java Development Kit (JDK) installed on your system and it must be version 7 or higher. <literal>M3UA</literal> uses Java SCTP which is available only from JDK 7 onwards. Connectivity to MSC/HLR is via SIGTRAN links (M3UA).</entry>
									<entry> </entry>	
									
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Database</entry>
									<entry>You must have Cassandra database (version 1.2 or 2.0) installed (Version 2.1 or later is not supported now).
									We strongly recommend that you use the latest version of 2.0 release because the support for version 1.2 will not be soon available, the most probably in the next release.
									&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; uses Cassandra Native Driver and therefore you should enable support for native drivers by setting the value of <literal>start_native_transport</literal> to <literal>true</literal> in the file <filename>apache-cassandra-&lt;version&gt;/conf/cassandra.yaml</filename>.
									Failure to do this may result in the Gateway not starting correctly.</entry>
									<entry> </entry>	
									
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Firewall Access</entry>
									<entry>You must ensure that you have appropriate firewall permissions to allow access to IP:8080. This is required to access the management consoles.</entry>
									<entry> </entry>	
									
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>SCTP libraries</entry>
									<entry>If you intend to use <literal>SIGTRAN (M3UA)</literal>, you must have the <literal>lksctp</literal> library installed. The Linux Kernel Stream Control Transmission Protocol (<literal>lksctp</literal>) library provides SCTP implementation.</entry>
									<entry>For more details on downloading and installing <literal>lksctp</literal>, please refer to <ulink url="http://lksctp.sourceforge.net/"></ulink></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
</para>
<important>					<para>
			
 You must ensure that the <literal>JAVA_HOME</literal> Environment variable is set properly for the user account(s) that will run the server. For more details on setting this variable, please refer to the appendix section.
					</para>
</important>
</chapter>

