<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter
	id="setup_downloading">
	<title>Downloading and Installing</title>
	<para>Installing &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is easy and quick with the binary download. You can either download the binary release or download the source code and set up from source.</para> 
	<section id="downloading_binary">
		<title>Binary Download and Installation</title>
		<para>The binary release is available for download at TeleStax Customer Support Portal <ulink url="&THIS.RELEASE_BINARY_URL;" /> </para>
		<procedure>
					<title>
						Binary Download and Installation
					</title>
					<step>
						<para>
							Download the zip file <literal>&lt;filename&gt;</literal> to any folder of your choice.
						</para>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>Extract the contents of the zip file.
						<screen>Downloads]$ unzip &lt;filename&gt;</screen>
						</para>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>Verify the contents of the newly created directory.</para>
					</step>
</procedure>
	</section>
	<section id="dir_structure">
		<title>Directory Structure</title>
	<para>
		When you download the binary release, you will notice that the top level directory is named <literal>mobicents-smscgateway-&lt;version&gt;</literal> and immediately below this are five sub-directories as explained below:
</para>
<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>cassandra: Contains description of the Cassandra database tables' structure.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>docs: Contains all relevant documentation in respective subfolders.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>jboss-5.1.0.GA: The core server with two profiles "default" and "simulator". The "default" profile is a clean profile where you will have to start from scratch and configure the entire SS7 Stack and SMSC Gateway. The "simulator" profile is a pre-configured profile to work with jss7-simulator. Refer to the Admin Guide for instructions on how to start the server in either of the profiles.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>resources: Contains SLEE MAP RA jars.</para></listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					tools: Contains SLEE tools and SMSC test tools as explained below.
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>RestComm-hlr-simulator: Command line HLR simulator used for load testing of SMSC. RestComm-hlr-simulator is pre-configured to integrate with SMSC run in simulator profile.</para></listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								RestComm-jss7-simulator: jSS7 Simulator that can be run in GUI or command line mode. This tool is useful to test <literal>MoForwardSM</literal> and other such functionality of SMSC like "when subscriber absent", etc. For more details on using this tool, please refer to RestComm SS7Stack User Guide. RestComm-jss7-simulator is pre-configured to integrate with SMSC run in simulator profile.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								RestComm-smpp-load: smpp-load tool is a Command line simulator to generate SMPP load. You must have <literal>ant</literal> installed to be able to run this tool. The smpp-load tool can be started to run as a SMPP Server accepting in-coming connection (BIND) from &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; or run as a SMPP Client to send BIND to &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;. You can confiugre this tool by editing the <filename>build.xml</filename> to define how many SMPP connections should be initiated, what kind of load should be generated, etc.				</para>
						</listitem>						
						<listitem>
							<para>
								RestComm-smpp-simulator: smpp-simulator is a GUI tool to generate SMPP load. It can only initiate BIND and act as a SMPP Client. You can also use it to test other functionalities like <literal>UCS2</literal>, breaking <literal>SUBMIT_SM</literal> into multiple SMS etc.
							</para>
						</listitem>												
					</itemizedlist>				
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

<screen><![CDATA[
|- mobicents-smsc-<version>
		|- cassandra
		|- docs
				|+ container
				|+ jss7
				|+ management-hq
				|+ resources
				|+ slee
				|+ smsc
				|+ tools
		|- jboss-5.1.0.GA
				|+ bin    //contains start up and shutdown scripts for the Server.
				|+ client
				|+ common
				|+ docs
				|+ lib
				|- server
					|+ default	//clean profile to set up from scratch
					|+ simulator	//pre-configured profile to work with the jss7-simulator
		|- resources
				|+ diameter-base
				|+ diameter-ro
				|+ map
				|+ sip11 
		|- tools
				|+ eclipslee
				|+ jopr-plugin
				|+ remote-slee-connection
				|+ snmp
				|+ RestComm-hlr-simulator
				|+ RestComm-jss7-simulator
				|+ RestComm-smpp-load
				|+ RestComm-smpp-simulator
				|+ twiddle
]]>
</screen>
  	
</section>
<!--End of Binary layout section -->			  
		
	<section
		id="source_code">
		<title>
			Setup from Source 
		</title>
		<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is an open source project and you have the freedom to build from source. Building from source means you can stay on top with the latest features. Whilst aspects of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; are quite 
		complicated, you may find ways to become contributors.</para>
		
		<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; works with JDK1.7 or above. In addition you must have the following tools installed.
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Git Client 1.6</literal> : Instructions for using GIT, including install, can be found at <ulink
								url="http://git-scm.com/book" /></para>
			</listitem>		
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Subversion Client 1.4</literal> : Instructions for using SVN, including install, can be found at <ulink
								url="http://subversion.tigris.org" /></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Maven 2.0.9</literal> : Instructions for using Maven, including install, can be found at <ulink
								url="http://maven.apache.org/" /></para>
			</listitem>	
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Ant 1.7.0</literal> : Instructions for using Ant, including install, can be found at <ulink
								url="http://ant.apache.org" /></para>
			</listitem>	
		</itemizedlist>
</para>
<!--TODO not clear for RestComm 
		<para>INSTRUCTIONS NOT AVAILABLE</para>-->
<!-- -->
		<section
			id="source_building">
			<title>Release Source Code Building</title>
			<procedure>
				<step>
					<title>Downloading the source code</title>
					
					<para>Use GIT to checkout a specific release source, the base URL is &THIS.TRUNK_SOURCE_CODE_URL;,
						then add the specific release version.
					</para>
					<programlisting>
[usr]$ git clone https://userid@bitbucket.org/telestax/mobicents-smscgateway.git 
[usr]$ cd mobicents-smscgateway
[usr]$ git checkout &lt;version&gt;					
					</programlisting>
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<title>Building the source code</title>
					<para>Now that we have the source the next step is to build and install the source. 
					&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; uses Maven 2 to build the system. You must ensure that <literal>JAVA_HOME</literal> environment variable is set properly prior to building the source.</para>
<programlisting>
[usr]$ mvn clean install
</programlisting>

				</step>
			</procedure>
		</section>

		<section
			id="trunk_source_building">
			<title>Development Trunk Source Building</title>
			<para>
				Similar process as for
				<xref
					linkend="source_building" />,
				the only change is don't switch to specific tag.
			</para>
		</section>

	</section>
</chapter>

